<resources>
    <string name="app_name">English In Profession</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main3">English In Profession</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Android Studio</string>
    <string name="nav_header_subtitle">android.studio@android.com</string>
    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="menu_ecp">English in computer operation</string>
    <string name="enVocForComButton">English Vocabulary for Computers</string>
    <string name="ButtonBooks">Books</string>
    <string name="ButtonTests">Tests</string>
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="monitor"><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: center; text-indent: 0; white-space: normal;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.e56fevd38gwk"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Monitor</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: 0; white-space: normal;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"> <span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;"> Monitor is the electronic visual display for computers. It is the most important output device of a computer. Without monitor we cannot see what computer is doing or performing inside. Monitor is also sometimes referred as computer monitor or computer display. Computer monitors are of two types: CRT (Cathode Ray Tube) monitor and LCD (Liquid Crystal Display) monitor.</span></p></div></string>
    <string name="printer"><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: center; text-indent: 0; white-space: normal;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.sxn8qrprmvwx"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Printer</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: 0; white-space: normal;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Printer is an output device used to print text, images, photos, or anything on a paper. The various types of printers include laser printer, 3D printer, Ink-jet printer, plotter, dot matrix printer, thermal printer, daisy wheel printer, line printer, etc. The printers print the text or objects on a paper either in black and white or colored form.</span></p></div></string>
    <string name="mouse"><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: center; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.n9alby40wft2"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Computer mouse</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">A computer mouse is an input device used for selecting items, opening, and closing items, copying and deleting the items on the screen by controlling the movement of a cursor or pointer on the computer screen. It is also used for creating new folders and browsing internet.</span></p></div><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">The mouse turns the movement of the hand (left, right, forward, and backward) into equivalent electronic signals that in turn are used to move the pointer. When you move the mouse with your hand on a surface, a cursor or pointer on the computer screen also moves in the same direction. For example, if we move the mouse towards right side, the cursor on the computer screen also moves towards right side. In the similar way, if we move the mouse towards left side, the cursor on the computer screen also moves towards left side.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Generally, mouse has two buttons: a primary button (left button) and a secondary button (right button). Clicking on the left button opens files whereas right button is used for copying files, deleting files, and creating folders. In between the two buttons, a wheel is present. This wheel is used to scroll down or scroll up on the screen.</span></p></div></string>
    <string name="speaker"><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: center; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.fcibbtqx2dsq"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Speaker</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: justify; text-indent: 0; white-space: normal;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">The speaker is an output device that converts the electronic signals from the computer into audio signals. The user easily hears these audio signals and understands it. Sometimes headphones are also used for listening songs and music from a computer. The speakers are  generally connected to a computer via cables. In some computers like laptops, the speakers are built-in.</span></p></div></string>
    <string name="memory"><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: center; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.n9alby40wft2"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Memory unit</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Like the human brain, computers also store the information. Memory unit is used for storing digital data for future use. Computer memory stores the information temporarily or permanently. </span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Computer memory is mainly classified into two types:</span></p><ul style="list-style-type: square; margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding: 0;" class="n8H08c UVNKR"><li style="margin-left: 15pt;" class="TYR86d wXCUfe zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Primary memory </span></p></li><li style="margin-left: 15pt;" class="TYR86d wXCUfe zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Secondary memory</span></p></li></ul><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.q58qt7qtbq9k"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Primary memory</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">The primary memory is used to hold pieces of program, data, and an instruction on which computer is currently working. It also stores the intermediate and final results of processing. After completing the processing, the obtained results are transmitted to the output device.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">The primary memory stores the data only when the power is on. When there is no power the data stored in the primary memory will be lost. The primary memory is also sometimes referred as main memory, temporary memory or volatile memory. This memory works faster than secondary memory. RAM is an example of primary memory. The primary memory of modern computers is made of semiconductor devices.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.dumtdc7me55w"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Secondary memory</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">The secondary memory is also called as non-volatile memory or permanent memory. It works slower than the primary memory. However, it stores the data permanently.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Secondary memory stores the data even if the power is turned off. Secondary memory has high storage capacity than the primary memory.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">The secondary memory stores operating system, text files, images, songs, videos, etc. The Central Processing Unit (CPU) does not read the information directly from the secondary memory. The information stored in the secondary memory is first transmitted to the primary memory. After that, the CPU reads the data from the primary memory. The secondary memory is much cheaper than the primary memory. Optical disks, magnetic disks, and magnetic tapes are examples of secondary memory.</span></p></div></string>
    <string name="keyboard"><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: center; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.tsnvn6igjxca"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Keyboard</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">The name itself suggests that it is a board consists of arrangement of keys. It is the main input device for most of the computers.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Keyboard is an input device used mainly for entering symbols like letters and numbers into a computer. Input is entered into the computer by pressing buttons or keys.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Generally, it is used for typing text and numbers on ms word, note pad, and other programs. Keyboards are also used for playing games.</span></p></div><div class="jXK9ad-SmKAyb"><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">A keyboard consists of several keys on which alphabets, numbers, and some other symbols are printed. To enter any text into the computer we press alphabetic keys whereas to enter numbers into the computer we press numeric keys. Most of the keyboards are generally attached to a computer via USB port. The keys or buttons of the keyboard is made of plastic.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Like the keyboards on a typewriter, computer keyboards have keys for numbers and letters. However, computer keyboards also have special keys.</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">The function keys are found on the top of a computer keyboard. The function keys of a computer keyboard include F1, F2, F3, F4, F5, F6, F7, F8, F9, F10, F11, F12. They perform different functions depending on where they are used. For example, Microsoft Windows users can use Alt+F4 to close the current program or shutdown the computer. F1 is used as the help key. When the user press F1 button a help screen is opened. Similarly, other function keys are also used for various purposes.</span></p></div></div></string>
    <string name="scanner"><div class="tyJCtd mGzaTb baZpAe"><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: center; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr" id="h.h0hzyphgrd4i"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Scanner</span></p><p style="margin-left: 0; margin-right: 0; padding-left: 0; text-align: left; text-indent: 0;" class="CDt4Ke zfr3Q" dir="ltr"><span style="font-family: 'Bitter'; font-size: 11pt; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: normal; vertical-align: baseline;">Scanner is an input device used mainly for capturing the printed documents and uploading it into computer as digital images. These digital images are easily viewed and edited on computer. A scanner can be connected to a computer via USB or SCSI.</span></p></div></string>
    <string name="cpu"><p style="text-align: center;">CPU (Central Processing Unit)</p> The CPU (Central Processing Unit) is considered as the brain of computer. A central processing unit is an electronic circuit that carries out the instructions of a computer program. It performs basic arithmetic, logical, control, and input/output operations. The user or human being writes a program to the computer. Computers do not have  intelligence, so they could not perform any operations on their own. Hence, all the instructions to the computer are given by the user to perform specific task. CPU controls operations on all parts of the computer including main memory. CPU is also sometimes referred as central processor, microprocessor, or simply processor. It is the most important part of a computer system. In all modern small computers, the CPU is placed on a single silicon chip. Hence, the size of CPU is reduced. CPU consists of two main components: ALU (Arithmetic Logic Unit) Control unit Arithmetic Logic Unit (ALU) Arithmetic Logic Unit (ALU) is a digital electronic circuit that performs arithmetic and logical operations. In some computers, the Arithmetic Logic Unit (ALU) is divided in two parts: Arithmetic unit (AU) and Logic Unit (LU). The arithmetic unit performs the arithmetic operations and the logic unit performs the logical operations. The various arithmetic operations performed by the Arithmetic Unit (AU) include addition, subtraction, multiplication, and division. Arithmetic unit performs these arithmetic operations at high speed. The various logical operations performed by the Logic Unit (LU) include NOT, AND, OR, NAND, NOR, XOR, XNOR, etc. The results of the ALU are stored in memory for further use. The results that are stored in the memory are passed to output devices. The control unit controls all the operations of the computer. It tells the Arithmetic Logic Unit (ALU), computers memory, input and output devices how to respond to the program instructions. It controls the flow of data between CPU and other devices. The control unit efficiently manages the resources of the computer to reduce power consumption. It also checks the correctness of the sequence of operations. The devices, which requires control unit, include Central Processing Unit (CPU) and Graphics Processing Unit (GPU).</string>
    <string name="headsets"><p style="text-align: center;">Headset</p>A headset can be an essential tool for communication, particularly when working from home, where you may need to block out surrounding noise just to get work done.</string>
    <string name="webcam"><p style="text-align: center;">Webcam</p> In 1991, the first webcam was up and running at Cambridge University\'s  <b>Computer Science</b> Department, but since then, webcams have crept into homes, businesses, public streets and buildings. Webcams are often used for personal use in the home by parents who want to give distant relatives visual access to their children or want to monitor what goes on in the home while they are at work. People might also use webcams in the home to keep an eye on things while they are out of town or even just to see what their pets do all day. The uses of a webcam are limitless. Businesses often use webcams for <b>video conferencing</b>, and webcam technology is used by numerous other entities to give the public access to a variety of information, from weather and traffic to the feeding habits of the most recently acquired zoo animal. Some schools and day care facilities use a webcam to allow parents to see what their children do at school.</string>

    <string-array name="englishVocComputerSpeakStrings">
        <item>ability</item>
        <item>accurate</item>
        <item>to affect</item>
        <item>amount of data</item>
        <item>approximately</item>
        <item>to attain</item>
        <item>available</item>
        <item>broadband connection</item>
        <item>to browse</item>
        <item>browser</item>
        <item>to carry out</item>
        <item>computer desk</item>
        <item>computer mouse</item>
        <item>(photo)copier</item>
        <item>to count</item>
        <item>CPU</item>
        <item>to crack</item>
        <item>dangerous</item>
        <item>data (datum)</item>
        <item>defense</item>
        <item>to deploy</item>
        <item>to design</item>
        <item>to determine</item>
        <item>dial up</item>
        <item>digital</item>
        <item>display</item>
        <item>to download</item>
        <item>drive</item>
        <item>electronic device</item>
        <item>electronic mail (e-mail)</item>
        <item>email accounts</item>
        <item>to enable</item>
        <item>to enhance</item>
        <item>essential</item>
        <item>except</item>
        <item>fast modem</item>
        <item>to find</item>
        <item>flash drive (card)</item>
        <item>floppy disk</item>
        <item>to handle</item>
        <item>hard drive</item>
        <item>infrared</item>
        <item>informational server</item>
        <item>to intercept</item>
        <item>interface</item>
        <item>keyboard</item>
        <item>laptop</item>
        <item>to last</item>
        <item>layman</item>
        <item>link</item>
        <item>to log in</item>
        <item>to matсh</item>
        <item>message</item>
        <item>memory</item>
        <item>monitor</item>
        <item>motherboard</item>
        <item>(the) net</item>
        <item>network</item>
        <item>obsolete</item>
        <item>operating system</item>
        <item>overload</item>
        <item>to perform</item>
        <item>player</item>
        <item>printer</item>
        <item>processing unit</item>
        <item>to provide</item>
        <item>provider</item>
        <item>query</item>
        <item>to receive</item>
        <item>reliable</item>
        <item>to respond</item>
        <item>scale</item>
        <item>to scan</item>
        <item>scanner</item>
        <item>search-program</item>
        <item>security</item>
        <item>to send</item>
        <item>set of instructions</item>
        <item>significant</item>
        <item>site</item>
        <item>society</item>
        <item>to solve</item>
        <item>source</item>
        <item>speakers</item>
        <item>storage</item>
        <item>to surf</item>
        <item>system unit</item>
        <item>tool</item>
        <item>to type</item>
        <item>to update</item>
        <item>user</item>
        <item>virtual reality</item>
        <item>voice message</item>
        <item>voltage</item>
        <item>window</item>
        <item>www (worldwide web)</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="englishVocComputerButtonStrings">
        <item>ability - способность, возможность</item>
        <item>accurate - точный</item>
        <item>to affect - воздействовать</item>
        <item>amount of data - объем данных</item>
        <item>approximately - приблизительно</item>
        <item>to attain - достигать</item>
        <item>available - доступный</item>
        <item>broadband connection - выделенное подключение</item>
        <item>tto browse - просматривать</item>
        <item>browser - браузер, окно просмотра</item>
        <item>to carry out - выполнять</item>
        <item>computer desk - компьютерный стол</item>
        <item>computer mouse - компьютерная мышка</item>
        <item>(photo)copier - ксерокс, копир</item>
        <item>to count - считать, сосчитать</item>
        <item>CPU - центральный процессор</item>
        <item>to crack - взломать</item>
        <item>dangerous - опасный</item>
        <item>data (datum) - данные, сведения</item>
        <item>defense - оборона, защита</item>
        <item>to deploy - использовать, употреблять</item>
        <item>to design - задумывать, придумывать, разрабатывать</item>
        <item>to determine - определить</item>
        <item>dial up - доступ к сети через модемное подключение</item>
        <item>digital - цифровой</item>
        <item>display - дисплей</item>
        <item>to download - загружать, скачать</item>
        <item>drive - диск, привод</item>
        <item>electronic device - электронное устройство</item>
        <item>electronic mail (e-mail) - электронная почта</item>
        <item>email accounts - учетные записи электронной почты</item>
        <item>to enable - давать возможность или право на ч-т</item>
        <item>to enhance - повышать, увеличивать</item>
        <item>essential - существенный</item>
        <item>except - за исключением, кроме</item>
        <item>fast modem - быстрый модем</item>
        <item>to find - находить</item>
        <item>flash drive (card) - флеш-диск (карта)</item>
        <item>floppy disk - дискета</item>
        <item>to handle - обращаться, иметь дело с</item>
        <item>hard drive - жесткий диск</item>
        <item>infrared - инфракрасный</item>
        <item>informational server - информационный сервер</item>
        <item>to intercept - перехватить (сигнал и т.д.)</item>
        <item>interface - интерфейс</item>
        <item>keyboard - клавиатура</item>
        <item>laptop - ноутбук</item>
        <item>to last - длиться</item>
        <item>layman - непрофессионал, любитель, ламер</item>
        <item>link - ссылка</item>
        <item>to log in - входить, подключаться</item>
        <item>to matсh - подходить, соответствовать</item>
        <item>message - послание</item>
        <item>memory - память</item>
        <item>monitor - монитор</item>
        <item>motherboard - материнская плата</item>
        <item>(the) net - сеть, (Интернет)</item>
        <item>network - сеть</item>
        <item>obsolete - устаревший</item>
        <item>operating system - операционная система</item>
        <item>overload - перегрузка</item>
        <item>to perform - выполнять, осуществлять</item>
        <item>player - проигрыватель</item>
        <item>printer - принтер</item>
        <item>processing unit - вычислительное устройство</item>
        <item>to provide - снабжать, доставлять; обеспечивать</item>
        <item>provider - провайдер, поставщик</item>
        <item>query - запрос, вопрос</item>
        <item>to receive - получать, принимать</item>
        <item>reliable - надежный</item>
        <item>to respond - отвечать, реагировать</item>
        <item>scale - масштаб</item>
        <item>to scan - сканировать</item>
        <item>scanner - сканер</item>
        <item>search-program - программа-поисковик</item>
        <item>security - безопасность</item>
        <item>to send - отправлять</item>
        <item>set of instructions - набор (свод инструкций)</item>
        <item>significant - значительный, важный, существенный</item>
        <item>site - сайт</item>
        <item>society - общество</item>
        <item>to solve - решать, разрешать; находить выход</item>
        <item>source - источник</item>
        <item>speakers - колонки</item>
        <item>storage - хранение</item>
        <item>to surf - просматривать различные сайты в сети</item>
        <item>system unit - системный блок</item>
        <item>tool - инструмент, орудие</item>
        <item>to type - печатать, напечатать</item>
        <item>to update - обновить</item>
        <item>user - пользователь</item>
        <item>virtual reality - виртуальная реальность</item>
        <item>voice message - голосовое послание</item>
        <item>voltage - напряжение</item>
        <item>window - окно</item>
        <item>www (worldwide web) - всемирная сеть</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="carMechanicsHeader">English for car mechanics</string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText1">A car mechanic is a service professional who maintains and repairs automotive vehicles. He or she might work on cars and trucks that operate using a traditional fuel like gasoline, or a non-traditional fuel such as ethanol or electricity. This type of mechanic\'s job may require expertise in all parts and components of a vehicle or the mechanic may specialize in a particular area such as engines, brakes, electrical systems or emissions equipment.</string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText2"><b>A mechanic may work for a shop that does tune ups and general maintenance</b></string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText3">Automotive mechanics may be employed by many different types of companies. Car dealerships commonly have a repair and maintenance department that employs mechanics. A car mechanic can also find work at repair shops, service stations and automobile leasing companies. Jobs of this type can also be obtained at car manufacturing plants where new cars require inspection before being shipped to dealerships. A significant number of car mechanics are self-employed.</string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText4"><b>Car mechanics should have good communication and analytical skills.</b></string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText5">Before the advent of high tech automotive diagnostic equipment, a car mechanic commonly had to heavily rely upon knowledge and experience to isolate automotive problems and correct them. Customers typically described the problem to the mechanic, and the mechanic put the car through a series of manual tests until the source of the problem was determined. After conferring with the customer on the options of repair and replacement costs, the car mechanic went to work to fix the problem.</string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText6"><b>A car mechanic can test or replace a vehicle\'s battery.</b></string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText7">Although a car mechanic today still benefits from hands-on experience, he or she is also generally required to know how to use electronic equipment and specialized software that helps diagnose automotive problems. This sophisticated equipment can be used to measure pressurized systems, analyze electrical system problems and diagnose engine and carburetor glitches. One of the earliest and most used electronic diagnostic systems analyzes automobile emissions to determine if they meet standards imposed by environmental protection agencies.</string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText8"><b>A car mechanic may choose to work at a car dealership.</b></string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText9">Success as a car mechanic normally requires good communication skills and good analytical abilities. Non-professionals commonly lack the language skills to clearly describe automotive problems, so a mechanic is regularly required to interpret their descriptions of a car’s malfunctions.</string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText10"><b>Car mechanics know how to use power tools, such as an air wrench</b></string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText11">A high school diploma or equivalent is usually required of potential car mechanics. Classes in computer operations, math, mechanical analysis and science are strongly preferred for aspiring automotive technicians. A considerable and growing number of employers require applicants for this position to complete an automotive repair training program at a local college or vocational school. Professional certification is also sometimes required to be hired as a car mechanic.</string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText12"><b>Car mechanics are responsible for replacing a vehicle\'s fluids.</b></string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText13"><b>Today\'s mechanics need to be able to interface with a car\'s onboard computer.</b></string>
    <string name="carMechanicsMainText14"><b>It became mandatory for cars to have on-board diagnostic computers in 1996.</b></string>
    <string name="car_anatomy_or_how_a_car_works">Car Anatomy or How a Car Works</string>
    <string name="learn_all_about_car_anatomy">Learn all about car anatomy, engine construction, transmission, steering, car body. There are answers on the questions: How a car works? How engines work? What is transmission? How the steering and braking system work?</string>
    <string name="car_parts">Car Parts</string>
    <string name="vehicle_consists_of_several">Vehicle consists of several main parts: the engine, the chassis , the car body, transmission and electrics.</string>
    <string name="let_s_study_the_main_units_and_component">Let`s study the main units and components of car:</string>
    <string name="car_body">Car body</string>
    <string name="the_car_body_is_the_main">The car body – is the main and most expensive part of a car. It can be carrying structure or some of it structural element.</string>
    <string name="car_engine">Car Engine</string>
    <string name="the_engine_is_the_heart_of_a_car">The engine – is the heart of a car. It`s energy source without car moving can`t be real. Engine consist of two mechanisms and five systems: Mechanisms of engine:\n1) Crank mechanism construction\n2) Valve mechanism construction Engine systems:\n1) Engine Cooling system;\n2) Engine Oil system;\n3) Engine Fuel system;\n4) Engine Ignition system;\n5) Engine Starting system.The chassis combines transmission, running gear, vehicle steering mechanisms.</string>
    <string name="car_transmission">Car Transmission</string>
    <string name="transmission_transmits_moment">Transmission transmits moment of torsion from crankshaft to drive wheels change the size and direction of it.</string>
    <string name="car_suspension">Car Suspension</string>
    <string name="running_gear_consist_of_the_frame">Running gear consist of the frame contains car body and all car mechanisms, the suspension (spring and shock absorber), rear and front axle and wheels.</string>
    <string name="car_steering">Car Steering</string>
    <string name="vehicle_steering_mechanisms">Vehicle steering mechanisms contains steering system, that change the direction of a moving vehicle, and brake system provides slow down and stop full of vehicle.\n\n«A Vehicle is a machine that transports people or cargo».\n\nVehicle anatomy is as interesting as human anatomy. Engine is a heart of car. Chassis are legs. Transmission – is osteo-muscular system. Car body like human body. As a man need organs as car need units, mechanisms, systems and parts.</string>
    <string name="car_repair_school">Car Repair School</string>
    <string name="in_order_to_explore">In order to explore how trucks and cars work you must consistently study materials of Vehicle Construction Book. Schema materials of website “Vehicle Anatomy” helps you to study it. So it would be nice if you study schematically material in the following sequence:\n\n1) Purpose of Vehicle (before exploring the construction and vehicle performance is necessary to know its purpose);\n\n2) Vehicle construction (the first step to examine the overall structure of the Vehicle, then you can begin to learn the device assemblies and other systems of the car);\n\n3) Operating of the vehicle (if you know the Vehicle anatomy you will be easier to understand how a vehicle works.\n\nIt is almost impossible to imagine modern life any more without car. Automobiles have improved modern life through providing more convenience to people and increasing efficiency. If you want to be car driver, you should know car anatomy.</string>
    <string name="types_of_engine">Types of Engine</string>
    <string name="types_of_design">Types of Design</string>
    <string name="basically_the_engines_are_of">Basically the engines are of two types, and these are external combustion engines and internal combustion engines.\n\n1. External combustion engine: In external combustion engine, the combustion of fuel takes place outside the engine. Example: steam engine.\n\n2. Internal combustion engine: In internal combustion engine, the combustion of fuel takes place inside the engine. Two stroke and four stroke petrol and diesel engine are the examples of internal combustion engine.\n\nThere are different types of internal combustion (I.C.) engine and there classification depends upon various basis.\n\nThe I.C. engines are classified on the following basis:</string>
    <string name="reciprocating_engine_in_reciprocating_engine">1. Reciprocating engine: In reciprocating engine, there is a piston and cylinder, the piston does reciprocating (to and Fro) motion within the cylinder. Due to the reciprocating motion of the piston, it is called reciprocating engine. 2 stroke and four stroke engines are the common examples of reciprocating engine.\n2. Rotary engine: In rotary engine, the rotor does rotary motion to produce power. There is no reciprocating motion. A rotor is present in the chamber which does rotary motion inside a chamber. Wankel rotary engine , turbine engines are the rotary types of engine.</string>
    <string name="types_of_fuel_used">Types of Fuel Used</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_types_of_fuel">On the basis of types of fuel used, the engine is classified as petrol engine, diesel engine and gas engine.\n1. Petrol engine: The engine which uses petrol for its working is called petrol engine.\n2. Diesel engine: The engine which uses diesel for its working is called diesel engine.\n3. Gas engine: An engine using gas fuel for the working is called gas engine.</string>
    <string name="cycle_of_operation">Cycle of Operation</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_cycle_of">On the basis of cycle of operation the engine types are:\n1. Otto cycle engine: These types of engine works on Otto cycle.\n2. Diesel cycle engine: The engine working on diesel cycle is called diesel cycle engine.\n3. Dual cycle engine or semi-diesel cycle engine: The engine that works on both diesel as well as Otto cycle is called dual cycle engine or semi diesel cycle engine.</string>
    <string name="number_of_strokes">Number of Strokes</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_number">On the basis of number of stroke, the types of engine are:\n1. Four Stroke Engine: It is an engine in which the piston moves four times i.e.2 upward (form BDC to TDC) and 2 downward (from TDC to BDC) movement in one cycle of power stroke is called four stroke engines.\nFour Stroke Engine\n2. Two Stroke Engine: The engine in which the piston does two times motion i.e. one from TDC to BDC and other from BDC to TDC to produce a power stroke is called two stroke engines.\nTwo Stroke Engine\n3. Hot spot ignition engine: This type of engine is not in practical use.</string>
    <string name="type_of_ignition">Type of Ignition</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_ignition">On the basis of ignition, the engines are classified as:\n1. Spark ignition engine (S.I. engine): In spark ignition engine there is a spark plug which is fitted at the engine head. The spark plug produces spark after the compression of the fuel and ignites the air fuel mixture for the combustion. The petrol engines are spark ignition engine.\n2. Compression ignition engine (C.I. engine): In Compression ignition engine there is no spark plug at the cylinder head. The fuel is ignited by the heat of the compressed air. The diesel engines are compression ignition engine.</string>
    <string name="number_of_cylinders">Number of Cylinders</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_number_of_cylinders">On the basis of number of cylinders present in the engine, the types of engine are:\n1. Single cylinder engine: An engine which consists of single cylinder is called single cylinder engine. Generally the single cylinder engines are used in motorcycles, scooter, etc.\n2. Double cylinder engine: The engine which consists of two cylinders is called double cylinder engine.\n3. Multi cylinder engine: An engine which consists of more than two cylinders is called multi cylinder engine. The multi cylinder engine may have three, four, six, eight, twelve and sixteen cylinder.</string>
    <string name="arrangement_of_cylinders">Arrangement of Cylinders</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_arrangement">On the basis of arrangement of cylinders the engines classification is:\n1. Vertical engine: in vertical engines, the cylinders are arranged in vertical position as shown in the diagram.\n2. Horizontal engine: In horizontal engines, the cylinders are placed horizontal position as shown in the diagram given below.\n3. Radial engine: The radial engine is reciprocating type internal combustion engine configuration in which the cylinders radiate outward from a central crankcase like the spokes of a wheel. When it is viewed from the front, it resembles a stylized star and is called a ‘star’ engine. Before the gas turbine engine is not become predominant, it is commonly used for aircraft engines.\n4. V-engine: In v types of engine, the cylinders are placed in two banks having some angle between them. The angle between the two banks is keep as small as possible to prevent vibration and balancing problem.\n5. W type engine: In w type engines, the cylinders are arranged in three rows such that it forms W type arrangement. W type engine is made when 12 cylinder and 16 cylinder engines are produced.\n6. Opposed cylinder engine: In opposed cylinder engine, the cylinders are place opposite to each other. The piston and the connecting rod show identical movement. It is runs smoothly and has more balancing. The size of the opposed cylinder engine increase because of its arrangement.</string>
    <string name="valve_arrangement">Valve Arrangement</string>
    <string name="according_to_the_valve_arrangement">According to the valve arrangement of the inlet and exhaust valve in various positions in the cylinder head or block, the automobile engines are classified into four categories. These arrangements are named as ‘L’, ‘I’, ‘F’ and ‘T’. It is easy to remember the word ‘LIFT’ to recall the four valve arrangement.\n1. L-head engine: In these types of engine, the inlet and exhaust valves are arranged side by side and operated by a single camshaft. The cylinder and combustion chamber forms and inverted L.\n2. I-head engine: In I-head engines, the inlet and exhaust valves are located in the cylinder head. A single valve actuates all the valves. These types of engine are mostly used in automobiles.\n3. F-head engine: It is a combination of I-head and F-head engines. In this, one valve usually inlet valve is in the head and the exhaust valve lies in the cylinder block. Both the sets of valve are operated by the single camshaft.\n4. T-head engine: In T-head engines, the inlet valve located at one side and the exhaust valve on other side of the cylinder. Here two camshafts are required to operate, one for the inlet valve and other one is for the exhaust valve.</string>
    <string name="types_of_cooling">Types of cooling</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_types_of_cooling">On the basis of types of cooling, the engines are classified as:\n1. Air cooled engines: In these engines, the air is used to cool the engines. In air cooled engines the cylinder barrels are separated and metal fins are used which provides radiating surface area that increase cooling. The air cooled engines are generally used in motorcycles and scooters.\n2. Water cooled engines: In water cooled engines, the water is used for the cooling of engine. Water cooled engines are used in cars, buses, trucks and other four wheeled vehicles, heavy duty motor vehicles. An anti-freezing agent is added in the water to prevent it from freezing during cold weather. Every water cooled engines has radiator for the cooling of hot water from the engine.</string>
    <string name="beside_above_types_of_engine">Beside above types of engine, the internal combustion engine is also classified on the basis of the following.</string>
    <string name="speed">Speed</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_speed">On the basis of speed, the types of engines are:\n1. Low speed engine\n2. Medium speed engine\n3. High speed engine</string>
    <string name="method_of_fuel_injection">Method of Fuel Injection</string>
    <string name="on_the_basis_of_method_of_fuel_injection">On the basis of method of fuel injection the engines are classified as:\n1. Carburettor engine\n2. Air injection engine\n3. Airless or solid injection engine</string>
    <string name="method_of_governing">Method of Governing</string>
    <string name="hit_and_miss_governed_engine">1. Hit and miss governed engine: It is an engine type in which the entry of the fuel is controlled by the governor. It controls the speed of the engine by cutting off the ignition and fuel supply of the engine at very high speed.\n2. Qualitatively governed engine\n3. Quantitatively governed engine</string>
    <string name="application">Application</string>
    <string name="stationary_engine_stationary">1. Stationary engine: Stationary engine is an engine in which its framework does not move. It is used to drive immobile equipment like pump, generator, mill or factory machinery etc.\n2. Automotive engine: These are the types of engines which are used in automobile industries. For example: petrol engine, diesel engine, gas engine are internal combustion engines falls in the category of automotive engine.\n3. Locomotive engine: The engines which are used in trains are called locomotive engines.\n4. Marine engine: The engines which are used in marines for boat or ship propulsion is called marine engine.\n5. Aircraft engine: Types of engine which are used in aircraft is called aircraft engine. Radial and gas turbine engines are used in aircraft propulsion.</string>
    <string name="electrical_system">Electrical system</string>
    <string name="earth_return_system">Earth-return system</string>
    <string name="apart_from_the_main">Apart from the main charging, starting and ignition circuits, there are other circuits that power lights, electric motors, the sensors and gauges of electrical instruments, heating elements, magnetically operated locks, the radio and so on. All Circuits are opened and closed either by switches or by relays - remote switches operated by electromagnets.\nCurrent flows along a single cable from the battery to the component being powered, and back to the battery through the car\'s metal body. The body is connected to the earth terminal of the battery by a thick cable.</string>
    <string name="in_a_negative_earth_system">In a negative (-) earth-return system, the current flows from the positive (+) terminal to the component being operated. The component is earthed to the car body, which is earthed to the negative (-) terminal of the battery.\nThis type of circuit is called an earth-return system any part of it connected to the car body is said to be earthed.\nThe strength of the current is measured in amperes (amps); the pressure that drives it round the circuit is called voltage ( volts ). Modern cars have a 12 volt battery. Its capacity is measured in amp/hours. A 56 amp/hour battery should be able to deliver a current of 1 amp for 56 hours, or 2 amps for 28 hours.\nIf the battery voltage drops, less current flows, and eventually there is not enough to make the components work.</string>
    <string name="current_voltage_and_resistance">Current, voltage and resistance</string>
    <string name="the_extent_to_which">The extent to which a wire resists the flow of current is called resistance , and is measured in ohms .\nThin wires conduct less easily than thick ones, because there is less room for the electrons to travel through.\nThe energy needed to push current through a resistance is transformed into heat. This can be useful, for example in the very thin filament of a light bulb, which glows white hot.\nHowever, a component with a high current consumption must not be connected using wires which are too thin, or the wires will overheat, blow a fuse , or burn out.\nAll the electrical units of measurement are interrelated: a pressure of 1 volt causes a current of 1 amp to flow through a resistance of 1 ohm. Volts divided by ohms equal amps. For example, a light bulb with a resistance of 3 ohms, in a 12 volt system, consumes 4 amps.\nThis means it must be connected using wires thick enough to carry 4 amps comfortably.\nOften the power consumption of a component will be stated in watts , which are found by multiplying amps and volts. The lamp in the example consumes 48 watts.</string>
    <string name="positive_and_negative_polarity">Positive and negative polarity</string>
    <string name="short_circuits_and_fuses">Short circuits and fuses</string>
    <string name="electricity_flows_from">Electricity flows from a battery in one direction only, and some components work only if the flow through them is in the correct direction.\nThis acceptance of a one-way flow is called polarity . On most cars the negative (-) battery terminal is earthed and the positive (+) one feeds the electrical system.\nThis is called a negative earth system, and when buying an electrical accessory a radio, for example check that it is of a type suitable for your car\'s system. Fitting a radio with the incorrect polarity will damage the set, but most car radios have an external switch for setting the polarity to suit that of the car. Switch to the correct setting before fitting.</string>
    <string name="if_the_wrong_sized_wire">If the wrong-sized wire is used, or if a wire becomes broken or disconnected, this can cause an accidental short circuit which bypasses the resistance of the component. The current in the wire may become dangerously high and melt the wire or cause a fire.</string>
    <string name="the_fuse_box_is_often">The fuse box is often located in a cluster of components, as illustrated here. The box is shown with the cover off.</string>
    <string name="to_guard_against_this">To guard against this, ancillary circuits have fuses.\nThe most common type of fuse is a short length of thin wire enclosed in a heatproof casing often glass.\nThe size of the fuse wire is the thinnest that can carry the normal current of the circuit without overheating, and it is rated in amps.\nThe sudden surge of high current in a short circuit makes the fuse wire melt, or \'blow\', breaking the circuit.\nWhen this happens, see if there is a short circuit or a disconnection, then install a new fuse of the correct amperage rating (See Checking and replacing fuses ).\nThere are many fuses, each protecting a small group of components, so that one blown fuse does not shut down the whole system. Many of the fuses are grouped together in a fuse box, but there may also be line fuses in the wiring.</string>
    <string name="series_and_parallel_circuits">Series and parallel circuits</string>
    <string name="a_circuit_usually_includes_more">A circuit usually includes more than one component, such as bulbs in the lighting circuits. It matters whether they are connected in series one after the other or in parallel side by side.\nA headlamp bulb, for example, is designed to have a degree of resistance so that it consumes a certain current to glow normally.\nBut there are at least two headlamps in the circuit. If they were connected in series, electric current would have to go through one headlamp to get to the other.\nThe current would encounter the resistance twice, and the double resistance would halve the current, so that the bulbs would glow only feebly.\nConnecting the bulbs in parallel means that electricity goes through each bulb only once.\nSome components must be connected in series. For example, the sender in the fuel tank varies its resistance according to the amount of fuel in the tank, and \'sends\' a small electrical current to the fuel gauge.\nThe two components are connected in series so that the varying resistance in the sender will affect the position of the needle on the gauge.</string>
    <string name="ancillary_circuits">Ancillary circuits</string>
    <string name="the_starter_motor_has">The starter motor has its own heavy cable, direct from the battery. The ignition circuit furnishes the high-tension impulses to the sparkplugs; and the charging system includes the generator , which recharges the battery. All the other circuits are called ancillary (subsidiary) circuits.\nMost are wired through the ignition switch , so that they work only when the ignition is switched on.\nThis prevents you accidentally leaving something switched on which might cause the battery to go flat.\nThe side and tail lights, however, which you may need to leave on when the car is parked, are always wired independently of the ignition switch.\nWhen fitting extra accessories, such as a rear window heater which consumes a heavy current, always wire it through the ignition switch.\nSome ancillary components can be operated without the ignition turned on by turning the switch to the \'auxiliary\' position. A radio is usually wired through this switch, so that it can be played with the engine off.</string>
    <string name="wires_and_printed_circuits">Wires and printed circuits</string>
    <string name="computer_components">Computer components</string>
    <string name="joiner">Joiner</string>
    <string name="joiner_is_a_man">Joiner is a man who makes joinery and works mainly at the bench on wood, which has been cut and shaped by the machinists. His work is finer than the carpenter’s, much of it being highly finished and done in a joinery shop which is not exposed to weather.</string>
    <string name="bricklayer_is_a_tradesman">Bricklayer is a tradesman who builds and repairs brickwork, lays and joints salt glazed stoneware drains, sets, chimney pots, manhole frames and fireplaces. He renders brickwork, including the insides of manholes. A sewer and tunnel bricklayer is a specialized bricklayer. He lays the bricks one on the top of another and puts mortar between them with a trowel .</string>
    <string name="bricklayer">BrickLayer</string>
    <string name="a_paper_hanger_covers">A paper-hanger covers interior walls or ceilings of rooms with decorative wallpaper or fabric, or attach advertising posters on surfaces such as walls and billboards. May remove old materials or prepare surfaces to be papered.</string>
    <string name="paper_hanger">Paper-hanger</string>
    <string name="job_holders_in_this_unit">Job holders in this unit group cover roofs and exterior walls with felting, sheeting, slates, tiles and thatch to provide a waterproof surface.\n\nTasks\nSeals edges of roof with mortar and ensures that joints are watertight.\nLays, aligns and secures successive overlapping layers of roofing material.\nLays and secures underfelt and covers with hot bitumen or other adhesive compound.\nCuts wooden battens, felt and underfelt to required size.\nMeasures roof or exterior wall and calculates required amounts of underfelt, tiles, slates or thatching material.</string>
    <string name="slater_and_tiler">Slater and tiler</string>
    <string name="plasterers_are_responsible">Plasterers are responsible for all of the tasks necessary to apply stucco and plaster to a building. They ensure that doors and windows are covered with cloths so they are protected from the mortar and erect the scaffolds when working on ceilings. Plasterers also mix their own work materials.\n1) Applies coats of plaster to interior walls, ceilings, and partitions of buildings, to produce finished surface, according to blueprints, architect\'s drawings, or oral instructions, using handtools and portable power tools: Directs workers to mix plaster to desired consistency and to erect scaffolds.\n2) Spreads plaster over lath or masonry base, using trowel, and smooths plaster with darby and float to attain uniform thickness.</string>
    <string name="plasterers">Plasterers</string>
    <string name="painter">Painter</string>
    <string name="house_painters">House painters and related workers prepare surfaces of houses and other structures for painting, apply protective and decorative coats of paint or similar materials, or cover interior walls and ceilings of buildings with wallpaper or other finishes.</string>
    <string name="facing_worker_tiler">Facing worker-tiler</string>
    <string name="glazier">Glazier</string>
    <string name="the_profession_of">The profession of a tiler is one of the most popular in the construction industry, and specialists in thfield can easily find a job in construction companies and enterprises.\n\nFacing worker-tiler\nfinishes building facades with ceramic and concrete slabs;\nperforms laying of stone and concrete steps of external stairs;\ninstalls bollards of fences and parapets made of hewn stone;\nperforms facing of embankments and bridge spans;\nperforms work on the installation of tiled floors and facing the internal surfaces of the walls of baths, laundries, sanitary units, bathrooms;\nsorts ceramic tiles by type, size, color;\nprepares solutions, cleans surfaces before laying ceramic tiles;\nrepair a tiled surface.</string>
    <string name="one_of_the_construction_professions">One of the construction professions is the profession of a glazier. This specialization is General construction, and the employee specializes in performing glass work, glazing wooden bindings with thin glass, thick glass and special brands of glass in the form of bindings. He is also engaged in the installation of double-glazed Windows, installation of fences made of glass blocks and fiberglass. He can also lead teams of glaziers in the construction, repair and reconstruction of structures and buildings.</string>
    <string name="plumber">Plumber</string>
    <string name="a_plumber">A plumber is a master of utility networks, a worker who is engaged in the repair, operation and installation of various sanitary systems for industrial and domestic needs.\n\nThe profession of a plumber requires the ability of a master to maintain three main sanitary systems: water supply; drainage (Sewerage); heating (steam or water). Sometimes people call plumbers plumbers, but they must be able to perform the entire range of work – from cleaning the bathroom drain and repairing the toilet tank to installing water pipes. Now the installation of individual heating boilers (gas, coal or wood) with a water heating system connected to them is very popular. Therefore, the master is required to improve their level of knowledge and master new promising areas of activity.</string>
    <string name="_10_simple_construction_site_safety_rules">10 Simple Construction Site Safety Rules</string>
    <string name="construction_sites_are_dangerous">Construction sites are dangerous places to work. Follow these 10 simple construction site safety rules to keep yourself, and others, safe. From wearing your PPE, to following procedures, you can help make your site a safer place to work, and prevent accidents. Construction sites are dangerous places to work. Every year, thousands of people are injured at work on construction sites. So, if you work in construction, it\'s even more important that you put health and safety into everything you do. Follow these 10 simple construction site safety rules to keep yourself, and others, safe.</string>
    <string name="_1_wear_your_ppe_at_all_times">1. Wear your PPE at all times</string>
    <string name="when_you_enter_the_site">When you enter the site, make sure you have the PPE you need. PPE is important, it\'s your last line of defence should you come into contact with a hazard on site. Hi-viz helps make sure you are seen. Safety boots give you grip and protect your feet. Hard hats are easily replaced, but your skull isn\'t. It can\'t protect you if you don\'t wear it. Wear your hard hat, safety boots and hi-viz vest as a minimum, along with any additional PPE required for the task being carried out.</string>
    <string name="_2_do_not_start_work_without_an_induction">2. Do not start work without an induction</string>
    <string name="each_site_has_its_unique">Each site has its unique hazards and work operations. No two sites are exactly the same. Make sure you know what is happening so that you can work safely. Inductions are a legal requirement on every construction site you work on. Your induction is important. It tells you where to sign in, where to go, what to do, and what to avoid. Don’t start work without one.</string>
    <string name="_3_keep_a_tidy_site">3. Keep a tidy site</string>
    <string name="construction_work_is_messy_slips">Construction work is messy. Slips and trips might not seem like a major problem compared to other high-risk work happening on the site, but don\'t be fooled. According to HSE statistics, slips and trips accounted for 30% of specified major injuries on construction sites (2016/17 – 2018/19). Remember to keep your work area tidy throughout your shift to reduce the number of slip and trip hazards. Pay particular attention to areas such as access and escape routes.</string>
    <string name="_4_do_not_put_yourself_or_others_at_risk">4. Do not put yourself or others at risk</string>
    <string name="actions_speak_louder_than">Actions speak louder than words. Especially on construction sites where one wrong move could put you in harm\'s way. Set a good example, think safe and act safely on site. You are responsible for your own behaviour. Construction sites are dangerous places to work. Make sure you remain safety aware throughout your shift.</string>
    <string name="_5_follow_safety_signs_and_procedures">5. Follow safety signs and procedures</string>
    <string name="follow_construction_safety_signs">Follow construction safety signs and procedures. These should be explained to you in your induction (rule number 2). Your employer should ensure a risk assessment is carried out for your activities. Make sure you read and understand it. Control measures are put in place for your safety. Make sure they are in place and working before you start.</string>
    <string name="_6_never_work_in_unsafe_areas">6. Never work in unsafe areas</string>
    <string name="make_sure_your_work_area">Make sure your work area is safe. Know what is happening around you. Be aware. According to HSE statistics, 14% of fatalities in construction were caused by something collapsing or overturning, and 11% by being struck by a moving vehicle (2014/15-2018/19). Don’t work at height without suitable guard rails or other fall prevention. Don’t enter unsupported trenches. Make sure you have safe access. Don’t work below crane loads or other dangerous operations.</string>
    <string name="_7_report_defects_and_near_misses">7. Report defects and near misses</string>
    <string name="if_you_notice_a_problem">If you notice a problem, don’t ignore it, report it to your supervisor immediately. Fill out a near-miss report, an incident report, or simply tell your supervisor. Whatever the procedure in place on your site for reporting issues, use it. Action can only be taken quickly if the management has been made aware of the problem. The sooner problems are resolved the less chance for an accident to occur.</string>
    <string name="_8_never_tamper_with_equipment">8. Never tamper with equipment</string>
    <string name="if_somethings_not_working">If somethings not working, or doesn\'t look right, follow rule number 7 and report it. Don\'t try and force something, or alter something, if you\'re trained to or supposed to. Never remove guard rails or scaffold ties. Do not remove machine guards. Do not attempt to fix defective equipment unless you are competent to do so. Do not ever tamper with equipment without authorisation.</string>
    <string name="_9_use_the_right_equipment">9. Use the right equipment</string>
    <string name="one_tool_does_not_fit_all">One tool does not fit all. Using the correct tool for the job will get it done quicker, and most importantly, safer. Visually check equipment is in good condition and safe to use before you start. Only use 110v equipment on the site. 240v equipment is strictly prohibited without prior authorisation from management and will only be used if no 110v alternative available and additional safety precautions are taken.</string>
    <string name="_10_if_in_doubt_ask">10. If in doubt, ask</string>
    <string name="unsure_what_to_do_or_how">Unsure what to do? Or how to do something safely? Or you think something is wrong? Stop work, and ask. It takes 5 minutes to check, but it might not be so easy to put things right if things go wrong. It\'s better to be safe than sorry. Mistakes on construction sites can cost lives, don’t let it be yours. If you need help or further information speak to your supervisor.</string>
    <string name="if_you_need_help_or_further">If you need help or further information speak to your supervisor.</string>


    <string name="builders_vocabulary_title">Builders vocabulary</string>
    <string name="literature">Literature</string>


    <string-array name="buildersVocabularySpeakingStrings">
        <item>arch</item>
        <item>architecture</item>
        <item>acetone</item>
        <item>beam; girder</item>
        <item>radiator</item>
        <item>concrete</item>
        <item>concrete mixer</item>
        <item>bolt; screw-bolt</item>
        <item>cobble; cobblestone; sett</item>
        <item>bulldozer; dozer</item>
        <item>bucket; pail</item>
        <item>veranda; gallery</item>
        <item>workbench</item>
        <item>vertical; perpendicular</item>
        <item>skylight; fanlight</item>
        <item>explosion; burst</item>
        <item>moisture; wet; damp</item>
        <item>humidity; humidness; dampness; moistness</item>
        <item>gutter; trough</item>
        <item>gate</item>
        <item>nut; screw-nut</item>
        <item>gas welding</item>
        <item>halogen bulb</item>
        <item>plaster; gypsum</item>
        <item>gypsum plasterboard</item>
        <item>grate; grating</item>
        <item>truck; lorry</item>
        <item>primer</item>
        <item>door</item>
        <item>dismantling</item>
        <item>wood</item>
        <item>design</item>
        <item>house; building</item>
        <item>board</item>
        <item>lumber; timber</item>
        <item>drill</item>
        <item>drain; drainage</item>
        <item>bow; arc</item>
        <item>shower</item>
        <item>smokestack; stack</item>
        <item>hole</item>
        <item>dowel; dowel pin; joggle</item>
        <item>reinforced concrete</item>
        <item>housing; lodging; living accommodations</item>
        <item>fence; fencing</item>
        <item>rivet</item>
        <item>putty</item>
        <item>stopcock; cock; turncock</item>
        <item>bar</item>
        <item>building</item>
        <item>lime; calcium hydroxide; calcium hydrate; lime hydrate</item>
        <item>insulation; detachment</item>
        <item>engineer</item>
        <item>tool</item>
        <item>inside; interior</item>
        <item>mortgage</item>
        <item>cable; line; transmission line</item>
        <item>bricklayer</item>
        <item>fireplace</item>
        <item>rosin; resin</item>
        <item>eaves</item>
        <item>helmet</item>
        <item>flat; apartment</item>
        <item>brick</item>
        <item>mallet</item>
        <item>valve</item>
        <item>glue; adhesive</item>
        <item>paste</item>
        <item>carpet; rug; carpeting</item>
        <item>mat</item>
        <item>well</item>
        <item>column; pillar</item>
        <item>compressor</item>
        <item>air conditioner</item>
        <item>container</item>
        <item>contract</item>
        <item>supervision; supervising; superintendence; oversight</item>
        <item>ditch; trench</item>
        <item>crane</item>
        <item>paint; colouring material</item>
        <item>roof</item>
        <item>sledgehammer</item>
        <item>lacquer</item>
        <item>laminate</item>
        <item>scaffold</item>
        <item>stairway; staircase</item>
        <item>ladder</item>
        <item>linoleum; lino</item>
        <item>sheet; plate</item>
        <item>elevator; lift</item>
        <item>shovel; spade</item>
        <item>chandelier</item>
        <item>painter</item>
        <item>marchioness</item>
        <item>trowel</item>
        <item>material</item>
        <item>sack; bag</item>
        <item>mosaic</item>
        <item>hammer</item>
        <item>mounting; assembly</item>
        <item>bridge</item>
        <item>pavement</item>
        <item>awning; sunshade; sunblind</item>
        <item>tilt; lean</item>
        <item>pump</item>
        <item>floor</item>
        <item>suspended ceiling</item>
        <item>surveillance</item>
        <item>noncombustible; incombustible</item>
        <item>carrier; bearer; porter</item>
        <item>wallpaper</item>
        <item>fireproof</item>
        <item>barrier</item>
        <item>support</item>
        <item>lighting; illumination</item>
        <item>hole; opening</item>
        <item>hue; shade</item>
        <item>office</item>
        <item>socket</item>
        <item>control; instrument panel; board</item>
        <item>arcade</item>
        <item>soldering-iron</item>
        <item>solder</item>
        <item>facade; frontage; frontal</item>
        <item>front; fore</item>
        <item>electrical switch</item>
        <item>bannister; banister; balustrade; balusters; handrail</item>
        <item>hinge; flexible joint</item>
        <item>plan; program; programme</item>
        <item>plank</item>
        <item>plastic panel</item>
        <item>mold; mould; mildew</item>
        <item>cooker; stove</item>
        <item>plate</item>
        <item>tile</item>
        <item>density; denseness</item>
        <item>bend; crook; twist; turn</item>
        <item>subsoil; undersoil</item>
        <item>contractor</item>
        <item>porch</item>
        <item>board; plank</item>
        <item>ledge; shelf</item>
        <item>crossbeam</item>
        <item>threshold; limen</item>
        <item>powder</item>
        <item>supplier; provider</item>
        <item>ceiling</item>
        <item>ground; land; soil</item>
        <item>deadline</item>
        <item>device</item>
        <item>hall; anteroom; antechamber; entrance hall; foyer; lobby; vestibule</item>
        <item>conduction; conductivity; conductance</item>
        <item>conductor</item>
        <item>design</item>
        <item>foreman</item>
        <item>cuboid</item>
        <item>bubble</item>
        <item>dust</item>
        <item>pedestal; plinth; footstall</item>
        <item>schedule</item>
        <item>layout</item>
        <item>railing; rail; lath</item>
        <item>socket</item>
        <item>rotunda</item>
        <item>tape-measure</item>
        <item>gasket</item>
        <item>welding</item>
        <item>pile</item>
        <item>bore bit; borer; rock drill; stone drill</item>
        <item>light-emitting diode (LED); luminodiode</item>
        <item>LED</item>
        <item>arch</item>
        <item>grid</item>
        <item>silicone</item>
        <item>sieve; screen</item>
        <item>siphon; syphon</item>
        <item>ramp; incline</item>
        <item>gradient; slope</item>
        <item>coating; coat</item>
        <item>dormer; dormer window</item>
        <item>mixture; blend; premix</item>
        <item>demolition</item>
        <item>agreement; contract</item>
        <item>vessel</item>
        <item>boilersuit</item>
        <item>loan</item>
        <item>shutter</item>
        <item>steel</item>
        <item>statics</item>
        <item>glass</item>
        <item>glass cutter; glass-cutter; glassworker; glazier; glazer</item>
        <item>table</item>
        <item>post; column; pillar</item>
        <item>stirrup; stirrup iron</item>
        <item>construction worker</item>
        <item>scaffolding; staging</item>
        <item>mortar</item>
        <item>construction (site)</item>
        <item>rafter</item>
        <item>joint</item>
        <item>subcontractor</item>
        <item>care; maintenance; upkeep</item>
        <item>thickness</item>
        <item>tunnel</item>
        <item>rip; rent; snag; split; tear</item>
        <item>walkway; sidewalk; pavement</item>
        <item>pipe</item>
        <item>chimney</item>
        <item>pipeline</item>
        <item>toilet; lavatory; bathroom; water closet; closet; W.C.; loo</item>
        <item>level</item>
        <item>installation; installment</item>
        <item>implement</item>
        <item>plywood; plyboard</item>
        <item>lantern</item>
        <item>mold; mould; cast</item>
        <item>antifungal (agent); fungicide; antimycotic (agent)</item>
        <item>foundation</item>
        <item>cement</item>
        <item>goblet</item>
        <item>loft; attic; garret</item>
        <item>tile</item>
        <item>spatula</item>
        <item>putty; filler</item>
        <item>hose; hosepipe</item>
        <item>stucco</item>
        <item>latch</item>
        <item>(power) shovel; excavator; digger</item>
        <item>electrician; line(s)man</item>
        <item>enamel</item>
        <item>energy-saving lamp</item>
        <item>floor; stor(e)y</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="buildersVocabularyStrings">
        <item>арка - arch</item>
        <item>архитектура - architecture</item>
        <item>ацетон - acetone</item>
        <item>балка, брус - beam; girder</item>
        <item>батарея (отопления) - radiator</item>
        <item>бетон - concrete</item>
        <item>бетономешалка - concrete mixer</item>
        <item>болт - bolt; screw-bolt</item>
        <item>булыжник - cobble; cobblestone; sett</item>
        <item>бульдозер - bulldozer; dozer</item>
        <item>ведро - bucket; pail</item>
        <item>веранда - veranda(h); gallery</item>
        <item>верстак - workbench</item>
        <item>вертикальный - vertical; perpendicular</item>
        <item>верхний свет - skylight; fanlight</item>
        <item>взрыв - explosion; burst</item>
        <item>влага - moisture; wet; damp</item>
        <item>влажность - humidity; humidness; dampness; moistness</item>
        <item>водосточная канава - gutter; trough</item>
        <item>ворота - gate</item>
        <item>гайка - nut; screw-nut</item>
        <item>газосварка - gas welding</item>
        <item>галогеновая лампа - halogen bulb</item>
        <item>гипс - plaster; gypsum</item>
        <item>гипсокартон - gypsum plasterboard</item>
        <item>грохот - grate; grating</item>
        <item>грузовик - truck (AmE); lorry (BrE)</item>
        <item>грунтовка - primer</item>
        <item>дверь - door</item>
        <item>демонтаж - dismantling</item>
        <item>дерево - wood</item>
        <item>дизайн - design</item>
        <item>дом - house; building</item>
        <item>доска - board</item>
        <item>древесина - lumber; timber</item>
        <item>дрель - drill</item>
        <item>дренаж - drain; drainage</item>
        <item>дуга - bow; arc</item>
        <item>душ - shower</item>
        <item>дымоход - smokestack; stack</item>
        <item>дыра - hole</item>
        <item>дюбель - dowel; dowel pin; joggle</item>
        <item>железобетон - reinforced concrete</item>
        <item>жилье - housing; lodging; living accommodations</item>
        <item>забор - fence; fencing</item>
        <item>заклепка - rivet</item>
        <item>замазка - putty</item>
        <item>запорный кран - stopcock; cock; turncock</item>
        <item>засов - bar</item>
        <item>здание - building</item>
        <item>известь - lime; calcium hydroxide; calcium hydrate; lime hydrate</item>
        <item>изоляция - insulation; detachment</item>
        <item>инженер - engineer</item>
        <item>инструмент - tool</item>
        <item>интерьер - inside; interior</item>
        <item>ипотека - mortgage</item>
        <item>кабель - cable; line; transmission line</item>
        <item>каменщик - bricklayer</item>
        <item>камин - fireplace</item>
        <item>канифоль - rosin; resin</item>
        <item>карниз - eaves</item>
        <item>каска, шлем - helmet</item>
        <item>квартира - flat (BrE); apartment (AmE)</item>
        <item>кирпич - brick</item>
        <item>клапан - valve</item>
        <item>клей - glue; adhesive (material / agent)</item>
        <item>клейстер - paste</item>
        <item>ковёр - carpet; rug; carpeting</item>
        <item>коврик - mat</item>
        <item>колодец - well</item>
        <item>колонна - column; pillar</item>
        <item>компрессор - compressor</item>
        <item>кондиционер - air conditioner</item>
        <item>контейнер - container</item>
        <item>контракт - contract</item>
        <item>контроль - supervision; supervising; superintendence; oversight</item>
        <item>котлован - ditch; trench</item>
        <item>кран (подъемный) - crane</item>
        <item>краска - paint; colouring material</item>
        <item>крыша - roof</item>
        <item>кувалда - sledgehammer</item>
        <item>лак - lacquer</item>
        <item>ламинат - laminate</item>
        <item>леса - scaffold</item>
        <item>лестница - stairway; staircase</item>
        <item>лестница (стремянка) - ladder</item>
        <item>линолеум - linoleum; lino</item>
        <item>лист - sheet; plate</item>
        <item>лифт - elevator (AmE); lift (BrE)</item>
        <item>лопата - shovel; spade</item>
        <item>люстра - chandelier</item>
        <item>маляр - painter</item>
        <item>маркиза - marchioness</item>
        <item>мастерок - trowel</item>
        <item>материал - material</item>
        <item>мешок - sack; bag</item>
        <item>мозаика - mosaic</item>
        <item>молоток - hammer</item>
        <item>монтаж - mounting; assembly</item>
        <item>мост - bridge</item>
        <item>мостовая - pavement</item>
        <item>навес - awning; sunshade; sunblind</item>
        <item>наклон - tilt; lean</item>
        <item>насос - pump</item>
        <item>настил - floor(ing)</item>
        <item>натяжной потолок - suspended ceiling</item>
        <item>наблюдение (видео) - surveillance</item>
        <item>негорючий - noncombustible; incombustible</item>
        <item>носильщик - carrier; bearer; porter</item>
        <item>обои - wallpaper</item>
        <item>огнеупорный - fireproof</item>
        <item>ограждение - barrier</item>
        <item>опора - support</item>
        <item>освещение - lighting; illumination</item>
        <item>отверстие - hole; opening</item>
        <item>оттенок - hue; shade</item>
        <item>офис - (business) office</item>
        <item>паз - socket</item>
        <item>панель управления - control; instrument panel; board</item>
        <item>пассаж - arcade</item>
        <item>паяльник - soldering-iron</item>
        <item>паять (припой) - solder</item>
        <item>передний фасад - facade; frontage; frontal</item>
        <item>передняя часть - front; forepart</item>
        <item>переключатель - (electric(al)) switch</item>
        <item>перила - bannister; banister; balustrade; balusters; handrail</item>
        <item>петля - hinge; flexible joint</item>
        <item>план - plan; program; programme</item>
        <item>планка - plank</item>
        <item>пластиковая панель - plastic panel</item>
        <item>плесень - mold; mould; mildew</item>
        <item>плита (на кухне) - cooker; stove</item>
        <item>плита (пластина) - plate</item>
        <item>плитка (кафельная) - tile</item>
        <item>плотность - density; denseness</item>
        <item>поворот - bend; crook; twist; turn</item>
        <item>подпочва - subsoil; undersoil</item>
        <item>подрядчик - contractor</item>
        <item>подъезд - porch</item>
        <item>половица - board; plank</item>
        <item>полочка - ledge; shelf</item>
        <item>поперечина (балка) - crossbeam</item>
        <item>порог - threshold; limen</item>
        <item>порошок - powder</item>
        <item>поставщик - supplier; provider</item>
        <item>потолок - ceiling</item>
        <item>почва - ground; land; soil</item>
        <item>предельный (по срокам) - deadline</item>
        <item>приспособление - device</item>
        <item>прихожая - hall; anteroom; antechamber; entrance hall; foyer; lobby; vestibule</item>
        <item>проводимость - conduction; conductivity; conductance</item>
        <item>проводник - conductor</item>
        <item>проект (графический) - design</item>
        <item>прораб - foreman</item>
        <item>прямоугольный параллелепипед - cuboid</item>
        <item>пузырь - bubble</item>
        <item>пыль - dust</item>
        <item>пьедестал - pedestal; plinth; footstall</item>
        <item>расписание - schedule</item>
        <item>расстановка - layout</item>
        <item>рейка - railing; rail; lath</item>
        <item>розетка - socket</item>
        <item>ротонда - rotunda</item>
        <item>рулетка (мерная лента) - tape-measure</item>
        <item>сальник - gasket</item>
        <item>сварка - welding</item>
        <item>свая - pile</item>
        <item>сверло - bore bit; borer; rock drill; stone drill</item>
        <item>светодиод - light-emitting diode (LED); luminodiode</item>
        <item>светодиодный - LED</item>
        <item>свод - arch</item>
        <item>сетка - grid</item>
        <item>силикон - silicone</item>
        <item>сито- sieve; screen</item>
        <item>сифон - siphon; syphon</item>
        <item>скат - ramp; incline</item>
        <item>склон - gradient; slope</item>
        <item>слой - coating; coat</item>
        <item>слуховое окно - dormer; dormer window</item>
        <item>смесь - mixture; blend; premix</item>
        <item>снос - demolition</item>
        <item>соглашение, договор - agreement; contract</item>
        <item>сосуд - vessel</item>
        <item>спецовка - boilersuit</item>
        <item>ссуда - loan</item>
        <item>ставень - shutter</item>
        <item>сталь - steel</item>
        <item>статика - statics</item>
        <item>стекло - glass</item>
        <item>стекольщик - glass cutter; glassworker; glazier; glazer</item>
        <item>стол - table</item>
        <item>столб - post; column; pillar</item>
        <item>стремя - stirrup; stirrup iron</item>
        <item>строитель - construction worker</item>
        <item>строительные леса - scaffolding; staging</item>
        <item>строительный раствор - mortar</item>
        <item>стройка - construction (site)</item>
        <item>стропило - rafter</item>
        <item>стык - joint</item>
        <item>субподрядчик - subcontractor</item>
        <item>техническое обслуживание - care; maintenance; upkeep</item>
        <item>толщина - thickness</item>
        <item>тоннель - tunnel</item>
        <item>трещина - rip; rent; snag; split; tear</item>
        <item>тротуар - walkway; sidewalk; pavement</item>
        <item>труба (для воды и т. д.) - pipe</item>
        <item>труба (дымохода) - chimney</item>
        <item>трубопровод - pipeline</item>
        <item>уборная (туалет) - toilet; lavatory; bathroom; water closet; closet; W.C.; loo</item>
        <item>уровень - level</item>
        <item>установка - installation; installment</item>
        <item>утварь - implement</item>
        <item>фанера - plywood; plyboard</item>
        <item>фонарь (крупный) - lantern</item>
        <item>форма для отливки - mold; mould; cast</item>
        <item>фунгициды - antifungal (agent); fungicide; antimycotic (agent)</item>
        <item>фундамент - foundation</item>
        <item>цемент - cement</item>
        <item>чаша - goblet</item>
        <item>чердак - loft; attic; garret</item>
        <item>черепица - tile</item>
        <item>шпатель - spatula</item>
        <item>шпатлевка - putty; filler</item>
        <item>шланг - hose; hosepipe</item>
        <item>штукатурка - stucco</item>
        <item>щеколда - latch</item>
        <item>экскаватор - (power) shovel; excavator; digger</item>
        <item>электрик - electrician; line(s)man</item>
        <item>эмаль - enamel</item>
        <item>энергосберегающая лампа - energy-saving lamp</item>
        <item>этаж - floor (BrE); stor(e)y (AmE)</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>